Coronet Magazine Records
Coronet Magazine Records
1935-1961
Esquire, inc.
68.0 linear ft.
Correspondence, manuscripts, dummies and editorial materials.
148904
Biographical History
Coronet was a general-interest monthly magazine published in the United States from October 13, 1936 to March 1971. It ran for 299 issues.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Coronet Magazine Records consist of manuscripts, editorial research files, and miscellaneous files.
Manuscripts cover 1957-1960. Editorial research files run from September, 1958 to July of 1960. Miscellaneous files include copies of Coronet and dummies, as well as assorted miscellaneous material.
Arrangement of the Collection
Manuscripts are subdivided by year and within that arranged alphbetically. Editorial research files are arranged chronologically. Miscellaneous files begin with the miscellaneous material (arranged alphabetically) followed by copies of Coronet, followed finally by dummies of the magazine.
Subject and Genre Headings
Popular culture; Publishing, printing and book arts; Coronet -- Archives.; Periodicals -- Publishing -- United States.; Journalism -- United States.; Correspondence.; Manuscripts for publication.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Esquire, Inc., 1961-62.
Inventory
- Literary manuscripts
  - 1955
    - A-Be (Box 1)
    - Be-Br (Box 2)
    - Bu-Ca (Box 3)
    - Ca-Co (Box 4)
    - Co-Da (Box 5)
    - De-Em (Box 6)
    - Ev-Fr (Box 7)
    - Fr (Box 8)
    - Fu-Gr (Box 9)
    - Gr-Hi (Box 10)
    - Ho-Hu (Box 11)
    - Hu-Le (Box 12)
    - Le-Ma (Box 13)
    - Mi-Ne (Box 14)
    - Ne-Pe (Box 15)
    - Pe-Ra (Box 16)
    - Ra-Sa (Box 17)
    - Sc-Si (Box 18)
    - Si-Ta (Box 19)
    - Ta-Wa (Box 20)
    - We-Zy (Box 21)
  - 1956
    - A-Al (Box 22)
    - Al-Ca (Box 23)
    - Ca-Cr (Box 24)
    - Cu-Cv (Box 25)
    - Fa-Fu (Box 26)
    - Ga-Ha (Box 27)
    - Ha-Ho (Box 28)
    - Ho-Ju (Box 29)
    - Ka-Ma (Box 30)
    - Ma-Mi (Box 31)
    - Mi-Ni (Box 32)
    - Ni-Po (Box 33)
    - Pr-Sc (Box 34)
    - Sc-Sm (Box 35)
    - Sm-Ta (Box 36)
    - Ta-Wi (Box 37)
    - We-Z (Box 38)
  - 1957
    - A-Ba (Box 39)
    - Be-Bu (Box 40)
    - Ca-Da (Box 41)
    - Da-Fi (Box 42)
    - Fi-Fr (Box 43)
    - Fr-Gr (Box 44)
    - Gr-He (Box 45)
    - He-Jo (Box 46)
    - Ka-La (Box 47)
    - La-Le (Box 48)
    - Le-Ma (Box 49)
    - Ma-Mi (Box 50)
    - Mo-O'C (Box 51)
    - O'G-Re (Box 52)
    - Ro-Se (Box 53)
    - Se-St (Box 54)
    - Wy-Z (Box 55)
  - 1958
    - A-Be (Box 56)
    - Be-Bu (Box 57)
    - Bu-Ca (Box 58)
    - Ca-Da (Box 59)
    - Da-Fa (Box 60)
    - Fa-Fr (Box 61)
    - Fr-Go (Box 62)
    - Go-He (Box 63)
    - He-Ka (Box 64)
    - Ka-La (Box 65)
    - La-Ma (Box 66)
    - Ma-Mo (Box 67)
    - Ni-Pe (Box 68)
    - Pe-Ro (Box 69)
    - Sa-Sk (Box 70)
    - Sk-To (Box 71)
    - To-Z (Box 72)
  - 1959
    - A-Be (Box 73)
    - Be-Bo (Box 74)
    - Br-Ch (Box 75)
    - Ch-Da (Box 76)
    - Da-Ev (Box 77)
    - Ev-Fi (Box 78)
    - Fi-Gu (Box 79)
    - Gu-Ho (Box 80)
    - Ho-Jo (Box 81)
    - Ka-La (Box 82)
    - Le-Ma (Box 83)
    - Ma-Mu (Box 84)
    - Mu-Ni (Box 85)
    - Ni-Ri (Box 86)
    - Ro-Se (Box 87)
    - Se-St (Box 88)
    - St-To (Box 89)
    - To-Z (Box 90)
  - 1960
    - A-Be (Box 91)
    - Be-Ca (Box 92)
    - Ca-Cr (Box 93)
    - Da-Fi (Box 94)
    - Fi-Ha (Box 95)
    - Ha-Ka (Box 96)
    - Ka-Li (Box 97)
    - Ma-Mu (Box 98)
    - Mu-Ni (Box 99)
    - Ni-Pr (Box 100)
    - Pr-Ro (Box 101)
    - Ro-Ta (Box 102)
    - Ta-Z (Box 103)
- Editoral research files
  - 1958, September-October (Box 104)
  - 1958, October-November (Box 105)
  - 1958, November-December (Box 106)
  - 1959, January-February (Box 107)
  - 1959, February-March (Box 108)
  - 1959, April-May (Box 109)
  - 1959, May-June (Box 110)
  - 1959, June-July (Box 111)
  - 1959, July-September (Box 112)
  - 1959, September-October (Box 113)
  - 1959, October-November (Box 114)
  - 1959, December (Box 115)
  - 1960, January (Box 115)
  - 1960, January-February (Box 116)
  - 1960, February-March (Box 117)
  - 1960, April-May (Box 118)
  - 1960, May-June (Box 119)
  - 1960, July (Box 120)
- Miscellaneous files
  - A-K, 1935-1954 (Box 121)
  - M-S, 1935-1954 (Box 122)
  - S-Z, 1935-1954 (Box 123)
  - Coronet magazine, 1955-1956 (Box 124)
  - Coronet magazine, 1957-1958 (Box 125)
  - Coronet magazine, 1959-1960 (Box 126)
  - Coronet magazine, 1961 (Box 127)
  - Coronet magazine dummies, October 1960 (Box 128)
  - Coronet magazine dummies, November 1960 (Box 129)
  - Coronet magazine dummies, December 1960 (Box 130)
  - Coronet magazine dummies, January 1961 (Box 131)
  - Coronet magazine dummies, February 1961 (Box 132)
  - Coronet magazine dummies, March 1961 (Box 133)
  - Coronet magazine dummies, April 1961 (Box 134)
  - Coronet magazine dummies, May 1961 (Box 135)
  - Coronet magazine dummies, July 1961 (Box 136)
  - Coronet magazine dummies, August 1961 (Box 137)